When I participated in Walpurgis,
I defeated Clayman, was formally
recognized as a Demon Lord,
and became part of Octagram,
the Eight-Star Demon Lords.
My business here is done. I'm leaving.
Leon and Valentine left as soon
as the conference ended.
Afterward, Guy put on a dinner party
for those who remained...
This is stewed black-furred tiger.
This is good!
The meat falls apart on my tongue,
and the sauce coats it...
Raphael-sensei!
Understood. Analyzing the recipe.
Looks like we don't need
to worry about manners here.
Hey, Milim! That's alcohol!
What's the problem?
It's my reward for pretending
to be manipulated!
Couldn't you have stopped
pretending sooner, though?
Clayman never did open up
about who was pulling the strings.
Indeed! But it was a welcome chance
to battle against Rimuru!
Hey!
You can't have this yet!
Meanie!
I'm the oldest Demon Lord,
despite how I look!
It really is good brandy.
It doesn't matter if it's alcohol
or anything else! It's nothing to me!
Is it made with grapes from Eurazania?
I'm impressed you could tell.
We can finally make it consistently now,
thanks to the fruit we import from them.
Well, then, I'll have one more!
You need to learn restraint!
Ugh, this is strong...
You're pathetic! Just watch this!
Valentine would definitely
like this. What a waste.
Gimme another!
Valentine, huh?
There was a lot I wanted to ask her...
Oh, well.
Notice.
Notice
Analysis complete.
It is now possible to recreate
the full dinner course.
I've got some of
the best recipes in the world,
and I made it through Walpurgis.
Lady Ramiris...
We must tell her about that...
And now, I've come back home to Tempest.
That Time I Got
Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 49: Demons and Strategies
We're open today!
Wait up!
Huh?
What's this all about?
When did you guys practice for this?
Great Rimuru!
Welcome home, Great Rimuru!
My most sincere congratulations
on your succession to Octagram.
Oh... Thanks.
Above all, I am so glad
that you have returned safely.
Wait, Diablo, what are you doing here?
Now, now. You must be exhausted.
For now, just take your
time recovering your energy.
Come in.
Pardon me.
Oh, is this matcha pudding?
Yes.
I'm not as good as Princess Shuna yet,
but I have gotten better at cooking.
Oh? I assume you brought some for me, too?
Of course, Lord Veldora.
Lord Veldora.
This is your promised portion, the first.
Diablo, you seem to be a man
with a strong sense of duty.
Diablo, aren't you going to eat some?
This is my payment
to him in return for information.
You need not worry about me.
Information?
Whistle, whistle...
I wondered how Diablo knew
about what was decided at Walpurgis.
How many desserts did you sell it for?
One? Two? Three?
Yep, three.
But, Veldora, you don't
even need to eat, do you?
D-Don't be ridiculous, Rimuru!
It's not a matter
of whether I need to eat or not!
I eat because I want to eat!
Besides, you don't need
to eat, either, do you?!
You did escort Great
Rimuru properly, I presume?
Of course I did.
I proved that he doesn't
need you as long as he has me.
But that aside,
what became of the task
Great Rimuru assigned to you?
Completed to perfection.
I don't get how you timed your
return so perfectly, though.
I was taking care of other matters,
but Lord Veldora contacted me
and advised me to return.
I-I just remembered
something I need to do...
Now, just sit tight, Veldora-kun.
W-Wait... You'll understand
when I explain...
Like hell I will!
Don't butt into other people's work!
No pudding for you!
Haruna-san, don't give
Veldora any snacks for a while.
What?! That's cruel!
That's too cruel, Rimuru!
I can't be bothered anymore.
Anyway, should you be wasting time here?
Is everything okay with Falmuth?
Hmph!
A tea server is better off serving tea.
Allow me to take care of this matter.
There will be no need for that.
With my informant on the job,
all is proceeding as planned.
It is?
Yes.
For starters, I restored all of them
to their original forms.
It was inconvenient
to leave them as lumps of flesh.
Lumps of flesh?
Oh, I get it.
My goodness.
Miss Shion is such a troublemaker.
What a hassle.
Healing magic is not even effective on you.
What sort of skill bends all
the rules to this extent?
I'll need to take some drastic
measures. Try to endure it.
You think the three in that carriage
are gonna make it to Falmuth in one piece?
I'm not sure you could say
they're in one piece now.
Thank you!
Thank you, Lord Diablo!
Shut up, trash.
Now, who's next?
Restore the king before me...
Return him to his original form...
Oh, yes. I nearly forgot you
were one of the prisoners.
Your name was Ramen...
I mean, Razen, correct?
You do understand, of course,
that asking a favor of me comes
at a very high price?
That's right... This man...
He's Noir, one of
the seven Primordial Demons.
But what's truly terrifying is...
that there's someone this demon serves!
Shion, don't overdo it.
A Demon Lord possessing a hidden power that,
while fleeting, surpasses imagination.
I knew in that moment
that the Kingdom of Falmuth
had awakened a sleeping lion.
Take me... no.
Please accept me as your
lowest-ranked servant.
I will devote every
aspect of my life to you.
So please, show King Edmaris mercy!
Very well, then.
However, I will not tolerate further
disrespect toward Great Rimuru.
If I detect any malice,
the king will not be the only one to die.
You can expect the breath of life to vanish
from the land of Falmuth itself.
Of course. My loyalty is yours alone.
M-Me, too!
I am the Archbishop
of the Western Holy Church!
I can surely be of use to you!
A royal mage who served
the royal family for so long
has at last turned his back
on the Kingdom of Falmuth.
You sullied Great Rimuru's
beautiful hands with human blood!
This is the fate you and I must bear.
I'm sure Razen's decision was the right one.
As the last king of Falmuth...
I swear to cooperate in any
way you desire, Lord Diablo.
Worry not.
So long as you obey me,
I will treat you well.
With my unique skill Tempter,
TEMPTER
preventing betrayal is a simple matter.
Hey, Diablo!
The prisoners are alive, right?
Not to worry, Sir Youm.
We will soon reach the capital of Falmuth.
Taking over a country is trivial.
Let us get it over with quickly.
S-Sure.
No matter what magic we use,
he won't return to his original form...
Shogo, what is the meaning of this?
Where are the other two?
What happened to the royal army?
Calm down. I'm Razen.
To protect the king, I cooperated
with the champion to escape.
What? You're saying that you aren't Shogo?
And you say the Falmuth army was defeated?
Don't tell me you failed
to subjugate the monsters,
and you had the nerve
to run back home in disgrace?!
What?!
Surely not!
What is the meaning of this?!
Calm down, gentlemen.
Let us hear what Sir Razen has to say first.
All of them went missing? Is this true?
It is.
Our army's battle with the monsters
awakened a dragon
that was sleeping in this land.
But the Western Holy Church said
the dragon was destroyed!
It was indeed destroyed,
but a dragon factor does not die.
The dragon will simply be
reborn elsewhere in the world.
We simply didn't expect it
to return so soon,
or in a place so close to us.
With the return of Veldora,
all the knights and monsters
in that area disappeared.
We were the only ones left.
Impossible!
It can't be...
Sorry I'm late.
I managed to convince you-know-who.
Who do you think you are?!
How dare a bunch
of commoners barge in here?!
Please hold, Lord Carlos.
They are the ones who saved us.
They saved you, you say?
What do you mean by that?
Allow me to answer that.
Archbishop Reyhiem!
When the two armies
clashed on the battlefield,
the battle that broke out was intense.
We had the advantage in numbers,
but it was no match
for the monsters' knowledge of the land,
and many of our men were lost.
The chaos that ensued must have been
the key to its resurrection.
With the sudden appearance of Veldora,
everyone there, both friend and foe,
was resolved to die
in the presence of the Storm Dragon.
But just then,
someone stood between us and the dragon!
That someone was
the monsters' leader, Great Rimuru.
Both Archbishop Reyhiem
and I were prepared to die.
But Great Rimuru convinced
Veldora to let us live.
He was able to speak with him?!
But just being in contact
with the Evil Dragon's dense magicules
means instant death for most living things!
So how...
Surely all of you are aware
that the monsters' leader is also
the ruler of the Great Forest of Jura.
He wasn't just calling
himself that on his own?
Most certainly not!
I saw the city of monsters myself,
and it was truly worthy of being called
the capital of a nation.
Even the Dryads, the guardians
of the Great Forest of Jura, serve him!
It was through the Dryads that
Great Rimuru negotiated with Veldora.
Dryads?
They are powerful monsters that
protect the land where Veldora sleeps.
He even commands beings as powerful as them?
If this Rimuru can negotiate
with the Evil Dragon,
we definitely do not want to
make an enemy of him.
Whoa, guys. You don't
have to worry about that.
I worked with Rimuru
when I defeated the Orc Lord.
He's friendlier than you'd think,
and he wants to live in harmony with humans.
Oh, then you can serve as the mediator
who conveys our demands to him.
I will let you know what they are later.
Wait in another room for now.
Hang on just a minute.
He's friendly under normal
circumstances, but not now.
And I'm pretty sure you know why.
Excuse me?!
You're the ones who declared war
on Rimuru's nation, aren't you?
That was a bad idea.
Some of Rimuru's friends
died because of that.
He's pissed as hell right now.
Watch your tongue, commoner!
If you have clout with this Rimuru,
that suits our purposes!
It's your duty as champion
to mediate for us!
So do something!
Lord Carlos, stand down!
Okay, first of all, listen to me.
You sent Otherworlders
to wreak havoc in his nation
without sending messengers
or declaring war first, right?
I went out there to try to make peace,
but when I heard about that, I was shocked.
Still, I was born here
in the Kingdom of Falmuth.
I didn't want to see my
homeland get destroyed,
so I pleaded with him
to make some sort of deal.
A commoner has no right
to speak of our kingdom's cause!
Listen here! I refuse to—
I told you to stand down!
You absolute moron!
You have no clue what went
down, so just butt out!
Listen to me, everyone.
What Sir Youm says is true.
We were defeated.
The only survivors were
Archbishop Reyhiem, myself,
and King Edmaris,
who was transformed into this
after coming in contact
with the Storm Dragon's magicules.
We were imprisoned,
and it was Sir Youm who
recommended we be set free.
The great Kingdom of Falmuth,
overpowered by a nation of monsters?
Yet we have no choice.
Do you intend to make
an enemy of the Storm Dragon?
Well, I...
Let us accept his offer. Right, gentlemen?
A wise decision.
Now, as promised, I will
set this nation's king free.
Who are you?!
When did you—
I do apologize, but you were wide open.
My name is Diablo.
I am my king Great Rimuru's loyal butler.
Your Majesty!
Wh-What is that medicine?
A full potion, a local
specialty of our nation.
The best healing medicine there is.
How are you feeling?
You've saved me. Thank you.
Now, King of Falmuth,
I have a message for you
from my king, Great Rimuru.
Speak, messenger
from the nation of monsters.
Very well. I shall.
"One week from now,
representatives from both our nations
will meet in this land to discuss peace.
I will give you options."
Options?
"Option one: your king abdicates the throne
and pays reparations to us.
Option two: you surrender to our nation
and become a vassal state.
Option three: the war continues."
He's mad...
"These are your options.
Please have your answer
ready within one week."
Wait a moment! That's not enough time!
Quiet.
I have a very short temper.
But we must summon nobles
from all regions...
I told you to be quiet.
What you want means nothing to Great Rimuru.
Understand?
So don't even think
about pulling any petty tricks.
You will not be permitted
to delay your answer.
If you give no answer in one week,
we will assume you intend
to continue the war.
Is that clear?
Now then, think very carefully
about your answer.
And that is what I did
to throw them off-balance.
You showed them that?
Yes.
I determined that it was the best way
to strike fear into them.
He wasn't complimenting you, Shion.
Now, as for the peace terms...
I demanded ten thousand stellar
gold coins as reparations.
It's no use...
Ten thousand stellar gold coins?!
I have no hopes or dreams left...
That's, uh...
100 million × 10 rows × 100 layers
Expressed in terms of Japanese yen,
the approximate value is one trillion.
Huh?!
Don't you think that was a bit unreasonable?
Not a problem.
I gave them three options,
but there is only one correct answer.
Surrender to Tempest
and become a vassal state
King abdicates and
pays reparations
War continues
The continuation of the war is impossible,
with their army destroyed.
And it's obvious that their nobles
will oppose becoming a vassal state.
Which means they'll choose
option one—reparations—
and they will make every
effort to negotiate.
Like, to lower the amount or let them
pay in installments for ten years?
We will not agree to lower the amount.
The Kingdom of Falmuth will have no choice
but to accept our terms.
They will most likely go about it by forcing
all responsibility upon a third party.
And what happens then?
Exactly what I've planned.
We should be able to collect ten thousand
stellar gold coins, at least.
How do you know?
Simple.
Stellar gold coins are so valuable,
they're difficult to use.
It's unlikely anyone would
accept them as payment.
I get it.
We'd have no way to use them,
so we'd have to save them up.
And what else are you plotting?
Choosing the first option means they
pay reparations and their king abdicates.
After abdicating, Edmaris will lose
the basis of his influence,
and he will be coerced
into assuming responsibility.
So he's the third party that
the nobles will force the responsibility on.
Now that their royal knights are gone,
opposing the nobles would
mean death for King Edmaris.
He'll have no choice but to do as they say.
But that would only be on the surface.
Behind the scenes...
With no military, the king's faction
lose to the nobles' faction.
And to avoid that...
Answer.
The optimal method is
to absorb Youm's faction
and maintain a cooperative partnership.
By doing so...
King Edmaris would have to
make an ally of Youm...
or in other words, allies of us all.
Precisely. Most impressive.
So we'd just need to lend
Youm some of our forces, right?
Yes.
I expect Razen to contact me soon.
Would that be enough for us to win?
What kind of face am I even supposed
Their next king won't form an alliance
to make right now?
with the surrounding nations?
Sir Fuze and King Gazel, their neighbors,
are using their influence
to put pressure on their other neighbors.
So the chances of that are very low,
but if it does happen,
I will handle it personally.
You need not worry.
Okay, I'll leave it to you.
Contact me if anything comes up.
Of course. Please leave
everything to me, my king.
Next time, "The Saint's Intentions."
The Saint's Intentions